# **PRASHANT RAI**



## Contact

#### **Current Address:**

E403, Orchard, Godrej Garden City, Ahemdabad, Gujarat

#### Phone:

+91 9654088086

## Email:

Prashantrai.alld@gmail.com

## LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/prashant-rai-01085324/

## Languages

English Hindi

## **Hobbies**

Reading, Cooking, Travelling, Listening songs.

## Summary

I have done MBA (Finance) with more than 11 years of post-qualification experience in Corporate Finance activities including Working Capital Management, Trade Finance, treasury, financial planning, Banking Operations, Limit setting, Credit Rating and analysis..

Strong background in Non Fund based and fund based Limits (new & renewal), project management and relationship management, poised to lever education & experience towards launching a successful career with a company seeking an articulate team player committed to manage team and supportive companies overall objectives.

## Skill Highlights

- Corporate Debt
- Trade Finance
- MIS Reporting
- Audit/Due Diligence
- Project management
- Strong decision maker

- Working Capital Finance
- Banking & Bank Liasioning
- Documentation
- Pre & Post banks compliances
- Quick Learner
- Team Management

## Experience

#### Associate Manager - Adani Green Energy Limited

(March 2022 to Present..)

- Leading Non fund Operation Responsible for non-fund operation (LC, BG, SBLC, Buyers credit etc.), planning and handling portfolio of INR 9000 crore by leading aAa team of 7 members.
- <u>Corporate Debt –</u> Raising new NFB line and renewal of existing banking lines.
- <u>Compliance</u> In charge of compliance and certificates for monthly, quarterly, half yearly & annual requirement of banks & financial institutions
- MIS Managing & Preparing monthly MIS for CEO review, working closely with other department to understand there requirement and preparing plan for future Couse of action
- Relationship Management Working on new structures with existing and new lenders for optimum utilization of funds and reducing overall finance cost.

## Manager - Rashmi Metaliks Limited

(Nov.2021 to Feb. 2022)

- <u>Corporate Debt</u> Raising non fund including LC, BG, WCDL & STL and cash credit debt (working Capital)
- MIS Managing & Preparing monthly MIS for CEO review.

## **Deputy Manager – ReNew Power Private Limited**

(April 2017 to Nov.2021)

- <u>Corporate Debt</u> Raising corporate Non Fund Limits including LC, BG, WCDL, STL and others
- <u>Project Finance</u> Debt fund raising for solar and wind power projects implemented by the company.
- <u>Credit Rating</u> Working closely with credit rating agencies to avail credit rating for company, project SPV's.
- <u>Security Creation & Perfection</u> Creation and perfection of security for project finance and corporate lenders with in prescribed timelines.
- MIS Preparation monthly debt dashboard for CEO/CFO review.

## Senior Manager - Kwality Limited

(April 2011 to March 2017)

- <u>Cash Credit Lines for Working Capital fund raising</u> Actively involved in raising CC limits with different public sector as well as private banks, conducting credit appraisal
- Monitoring Reconciliation of loan a/c, bank, cash, interest & foreign remittance
- <u>Banking -</u> Liasoning with banks, Handling Banking Operations on behalf of company, Handling queries of banks and financial institutions for their various concerns under their credit and risk analysis and taking prompt action on them

#### **Education**

MBA- Finance: 2011 – Delhi Business School (PTU) – 2year full time regular.

Bachelor of Commerce: 2008 - Allahabad University

School: ISC (2005), ICSE (2003), Jyoti Niketan School, Azamgarh, UP.